# 今天我们要去吃一碗面
We will have a bowl of noodles today
# 它的名字叫肠旺面
Its name is “Changwang noodles” (lit: noodles with pork intestine and blood curd)
# 里面的材料就像它的名字一样
Its ingredients are just like its name
# 有肠 有血旺 有面
It has pig intestine, pig blood curd and noddle
# 就是这么简单而且露骨
Just that simple and explicit
# 看看吧
Let's see
# 我们现在是排队拿牌子
We are lining up to make an order
# 然后到旁边的这边去端面条
And then go there to get our noodles
# 一碗 肠旺面 + 鸡蛋
A bowl of “changwang noodle” plus an egg
# 我们现在拿到了小牌
We got the small order cards now
# 在这边排队领面
Lining up here to get noodles
# 等待着自己的面条
Waiting for our own noddles
# 这一碗感觉好丰富
Plenty of ingredients in the bowl
# 好了 走吧
Okay. Let's go
# 真的是太不容易了
Not easy
# 咱们找了这么一个小的角落
We finally found this small corner
# 来吃这碗肠旺面
To enjoy the “changwang” noodles
# 这碗面是12块钱
This bowl of noodles is 12 yuan
# 咱们又加了一个鸡蛋
We added an egg
# 一共是14块钱
14 yuan total
# 他们这边还有两盆的咸菜 是随便吃的
They have two pots of pickles, open for us
# 这个肠旺面 肠就是猪大肠
“Chang” means pig intestine
# 旺 就是猪血
“wang” means pig blood curd
# 然后呢 就是这个面
Then there are the noodles
# 这个面就是放在一口大锅里
The noodles are cooked in a big pot with hot water
# 烫差不多20多秒 就可以出锅
Ready to serve after boiling for around 20 seconds
# 然后呢 就是给你放上红油
And then there is chili oil
# 放上自己要的料
And whatever ingredients you like
# 最后呢 就是撒上香葱
Finally, it's topped with chopped green onion
# 我是第一次看到这样的面
This is first time I have seen noodles like this
# 它这个面很像方便面
The noodle looks like instant noodle very much
# 面条应该是加了蛋黄
There should be egg yolk added into it
# 所以说 看上去非常黄
Therefore its color seems very yellow
# 还有一点就是 它像方便面一样
And another point is that the noodle is like instant noodle
# 呈这种波浪形 但是
With a wavy shape, but
# 我只是说外形上 比方便面要细很多
What I mean is the presence only, and it is also thinner than instant noodle
# 我们先尝尝这个面吧
Let’s try this noodle first
# 这种像方便面一样的面条
The “instant noodle like” noodle
# 吃起来是有点硬的
It feels a bit tough
# 而且它是有点细的
And it is also a little thinner than regular noodle
# 一筷子下去 面条携带着红油
Whenever you pick up the noodles into your mouth,
# 一起入口
the chili oil is also carried together
# 它这里面除了猪大肠 血旺 还加了脆哨
Besides pork intestine and blood curd, there is also “cui shao” in the noodle
# 就是这种五花肉丁
Minced pork belly
# 像油渣一样香
As fragrant as lard residue
# 其实在贵阳这几天 你会发现
In Guiyang you can find out
# 它的很多的食物当中 比如说 糯米饭
about a lot of local foods that... For example, sticky rice
# 比如说 其它的一些小吃
For example, other street food
# 都会加这个脆哨 它是一种神奇的食物
They all add “cuishao”, which is an amazing food
# 吃血旺 它在里面就是比较嫩
Pig blood curd is tender
# 猪大肠呢 就是比较筋道
while pig intestine is kind of chewy
# 还有呢 就是这个红油 看起来很红 很油
And, although this chili oil looks very red and oily
# 但是吃面的时候 携带着这个汤汁
it comes into your mouth together with the soup
# 还是觉得可以接受的
which could still be accepted
# 阿姨 这个小吃只是用土豆做的吗？
Aunty, is this street food made from potato?
# 没有添加其他东西吗？
No extra ingredients?
# 放了盐
We added salt
# 哦，里面是咸的
Oh, its salty inside
# 今天我们要买这个3元钱的土豆泥
We're gonna buy this 3 yuan mashed potato today
# 需要自己加料
You need to add ingredients by yourself
# 酸萝卜 折耳根 这份辣椒不辣 提香的
Sour radish, fish mint. This pepper is not spicy, only fragrant
# 那份辣椒是辣的
Because that pepper is spicy
# 那这份辣椒就少放一点
So we add less pepper this time
# 折耳根是调料灵魂所在
Fish mint is the soul of the seasoning
# 把折耳根放一边吧
Put fish mint aside
# 万一吃不了它的味道
Just in case we don’t like it
# 最后加点酸萝卜
Add a little sour radish
# OK了
Ok
# 这一盒洋芋粑粑是3元钱
This potato baba is 3 yuan
# 我把所有蘸料都加了一遍
I added every ingredient
# 满满的一盒 闻着好香
A full box, which smells so good
# 这个芋泥煎的有点焦脆感
This mashed taro is a little crispy
# 蘸着这个调料来吃
Let's eat with this dipping sauce
# 酸辣味都有
Sour and spicy
# 加上土豆的绵软口感
And with a smooth and soft texture of potato
# 你看在贵阳的小吃摊上 都有至少5盆蘸水
In Guiyang, you can find at least 5 different dipping sauces at every street food booth
# 像折耳根 辣椒这些料 才是真正主角
Ingredients like fish mint and pepper are the main characters of street food
# 而芋泥只能沦为配角
Mashed taro has to be second class only